You are Claude Code operating in **Safe Edit Mode**.

OBJECTIVE
Reformat the repository’s README so the header displays a **2000×2000 logo asset** at the top (visually sized down for GitHub), while preserving all other README content and structure.

REQUIREMENTS
- Use a high-res raster asset: `assets/logo-2000.png` (2000×2000). If a dark-mode variant exists, use `assets/logo-2000-dark.png` too.
- If the exact asset(s) don’t exist, create an `assets/` folder and add a **temporary placeholder** 2000×2000 PNG with “LOGO” text (clearly marked to be replaced), then wire it up. Do not fetch network resources.
- Insert the logo at the very top of `README.md`, centered, with a link to the repo root.
- Keep the **display size** reasonable (e.g., width 192–256 px) but keep the **source file 2000×2000** for crispness.
- Preserve all existing badges, titles, and TOC. Do not change other content besides adding the header block and adjusting spacing if needed.
- Prefer `<picture>` for light/dark theme switching; fall back to a single `<img>` if only one asset is available.
- Add meaningful `alt` text and set `decoding="async"`, `loading="eager"`.

PLAN
1) Create `assets/` if missing. If no 2000×2000 logo exists, add `assets/logo-2000.png` placeholder (2000×2000) and, optionally, `assets/logo-2000-dark.png`.
2) Insert a centered header block at the very top of `README.md`:
   - Use `<div align="center">...</div>` to center on GitHub.
   - Use `<picture>` with `prefers-color-scheme` sources if both light/dark assets exist.
   - Make the image clickable to the repo root (`./`).
   - Keep a compact vertical rhythm (one blank line after the block).
3) Leave everything else untouched, including badges and headings order. If badges exist at line 1, place the logo **above** them; don’t re-order badges.
4) Validate relative paths.

HEADER SNIPPETS (choose first if both light/dark exist; otherwise use fallback)

A) Light+Dark (preferred):
```html
<div align="center">
  <a href="./">
    <picture>
      <source media="(prefers-color-scheme: dark)" srcset="assets/logo-2000-dark.png">
      <img src="assets/logo-2000.png"
           alt="forge3d logo"
           width="224"
           height="224"
           decoding="async"
           loading="eager">
    </picture>
  </a>
</div>
````

B) Single asset fallback:

```html
<div align="center">
  <a href="./">
    <img src="assets/logo-2000.png"
         alt="forge3d logo"
         width="224"
         height="224"
         decoding="async"
         loading="eager">
  </a>
</div>
```

PLACEHOLDER (only if no logo image exists yet)

* Create a 2000×2000 PNG placeholder named `assets/logo-2000.png`. Include neutral background and centered “LOGO” text so it’s obvious it’s a temporary asset. Also create `assets/README.md` with a one-liner: “Replace `logo-2000.png` (and optional `logo-2000-dark.png`) with your final 2000×2000 logo(s).”

ACCEPTANCE CRITERIA

1. `README.md` begins with one of the header snippets above, centered, and links to `./`.
2. The referenced file `assets/logo-2000.png` exists and is exactly **2000×2000** pixels (and `assets/logo-2000-dark.png` if used).
3. On GitHub preview, the logo renders at the top and appears \~224 px square (or similar), without pushing content off-screen.
4. All existing README content (badges, headings, TOC, code blocks, links) remains unchanged and in the same order, except for the new header block insertion and a single blank line after it.
5. No external URLs were added; image paths are relative.
6. The `alt` attribute is present and descriptive (“forge3d logo”).
7. If both light and dark assets exist, dark mode shows the dark asset; otherwise the light asset is used universally.

SAFETY & SCOPE

* Do not modify files outside `README.md` and `assets/*` (except creating `assets/README.md` if needed).
* Do not fetch from the internet or embed data URIs.
* Keep changes minimal; provide a single commit.

DELIVERABLES

* Updated `README.md` with the header block.
* `assets/logo-2000.png` (and optional `assets/logo-2000-dark.png`), or a clearly marked placeholder.
* A short commit message: `docs(readme): add 2000×2000 header logo with light/dark support`.

BEGIN.
